<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aesthetic Perception &amp; Cognition</title>
    <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Aesthetic Perception &amp; Cognition</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 12:20:58 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bibliography Art and Life</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/teaching/artlife-bibliography/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 12:20:58 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/teaching/artlife-bibliography/</guid>
      <description>These texts all concern the place of aesthetics in our lives in one way or antoher. Think of the aesthetic value realised in good character, in good urban planning, in one’s personal style, of the ugliness of consumerism, etc.
This bibliography is associated with the reading group on The Aesthetic Life.
Core reading Jun&amp;rsquo;ichirō Tanizaki 1977 [1933], In Praise of Shadows. Thomas J. Harper and Edward G. Seidensticker (trans.) Walter Pater (1868), From ‘Poems by William Morris’, in The Aesthetes: A Sourcebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference | Call for Abstracts</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/conference-2022-cfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/conference-2022-cfp/</guid>
      <description>Aesthetic Perception and Cognition Date: October 20–21, 2022
Venue: Uppsala University
Organisers: Elisabeth Schellekens, Maarten Steenhagen
Submission deadline: 1st of July 2022
Conference description: The purpose of this conference is to reconsider one of the cornerstones of philosophical aesthetics: the idea that aesthetics is fundamentally about a form of perception. This assumption has crucial implications for our understanding both of the nature of aesthetic value and of how we form beliefs about such value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foundations of the perceptual model</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/reading-group-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/reading-group-2022/</guid>
      <description>Where does the idea that aesthetic judgment is about perception or sensation come from? What is the motivation for excluding cognitive or intellectual forms of engagement from the aesthetic? Are there authors who subvert this close tie between aesthetics and the senses? In this reading group we read a variety of authors who have acknowledged intelligible forms of beauty.
Meeting time: Tuesdays 12:30-14:00 (fortnightly)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop Aesthetic Practices</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/workshop2021jan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/workshop2021jan/</guid>
      <description>The Aesthetics Perception and Cognition Project organises a one-day, online workshop, which will take place on the 12th of January 2020. The theme of the workshop is Aesthetic Practices. For more information about the workshop, and about how to participate via Zoom, please get in touch with maarten.steenhagen@filosofi.uu.se
Workshop: Aesthetic Practices, 12 January 2021 Schedule : Welcome: 10:00-10:15
Session A: 10:15-11:15 Jon Robson &amp;lsquo;Over-Appreciating Appreciation&amp;rsquo; (Co-author Rebecca Wallbank) Response: Nick Wiltsher Virtual coffee break: 11:15-11:30</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Aesthetic Life</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/reading-group-autumn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/reading-group-autumn/</guid>
      <description>Think of the aesthetic value realised in good character, in good urban planning, in one’s personal style, of the ugliness of consumerism, etc. What is the place of such values in our lives? And what is the place of those values in a theory of aesthetic experience or judgment?
Discussing the place of aesthetic value in our lives, broadly construed, is likely to help us to be more critical of the idea that aesthetic experience is at root sensory or perceptual, considering life is about so much more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Controlling (mental) images and aesthetic perception of racialized bodies</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/mental-images-racialized-bodies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/mental-images-racialized-bodies/</guid>
      <description>The aesthetic evaluation of human bodies is part and parcel of our everyday lives. Not only do we judge, for example, the elegance of Isaac Hernández as he dances in Le Corsaire, but we take notice of a stranger&#39;s beauty while walking down the street, or even a colleague&#39;s scruffiness as they walk into a meeting. These evaluations concern human bodies treated as aesthetic objects, objects that invite certain responses or attitudes as a result of being perceived as having specific aesthetic properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beauty. Some Reflections on the Broad/Narrow Distinction</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/beauty-broad-narrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/beauty-broad-narrow/</guid>
      <description>In this post I&#39;d like to bring up for discussion some thoughts on the distinction between a so-called narrow sense of beauty&amp;mdash;a specific quality or value&amp;mdash;and a broad one&amp;mdash;comprising aesthetic value or positive aesthetic qualities in general. This distinction is often acknowledged in contemporary analytic aesthetics, but rarely examined. I think that it&#39;s an important distinction, partly because it encapsulates some key tensions in modern aesthetics, and partly because it&#39;s a good starting point on which to start thinking about how to build a theory of beauty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authenticity and Make-believe in Competitive Games</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/authenticity-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/authenticity-games/</guid>
      <description>Well, Euro 2020 has been and gone. Or rather it would have, had COVID-19 not swept it from the calendar along with all of humanity&#39;s non-banana-bread-baking hopes and dreams. Despite being 35 years old (yesterday was, incidentally my birthday), I would ordinarily be unable to contain my infantile excitement for the Euros. I have supported the country of my birth, Germany, since I was 6 when, alas, they faltered to Denmark (yes, you read that right) in the final of Euro &#39;92 (in Sweden, no less!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photographic Phenomenology in the Digital Age</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/photographic-phenomenology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/photographic-phenomenology/</guid>
      <description>Post-photographic theorists feared that the epistemic standing of photography would wane with the advent of digital post-processing (Mitchell 1998; Richin 2010; Savedoff 2008). Evidence suggests however, that despite the knowledge that digital photographs can be easily and convincingly manipulated (although not always – just search &amp;quot;Photoshop fails&amp;quot;), viewers continue to subsume the contents of photographs as veridical. In fact, several studies into the efficacy of different methods of visual literacy, to counteract the negative effects of altered photographs on body image, have seen a &amp;quot;boomerang effect&amp;quot; (Bissell 2006; Harrison and Hefner 2014).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The interactive character of installation art</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/interactive-installation-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/interactive-installation-art/</guid>
      <description>Works of installation art are structured around the beholders, who are invited to explore their spaces and the objects possibly placed within those (see e.g. Reiss 1999; Rebentisch 2003; Bishop 2005; Ring Petersen 2015).
Think of Robert Irwin&amp;rsquo;s Untitled (1971). The work is displayed by hanging a rectangular, transparent cloth from the ceiling of an empty gallery room and anchoring it to the floor, to keep it stretched and wrinkleless. The cloth hangs obliquely – its lower rim is closer to the back wall of the room than its upper rim – and is as wide as the back wall: the beholders cannot reach the back wall, but they can get close to the cloth, which creates a space with a very sloping roof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metaphor and conceptual art</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/metaphor-conceptual-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/metaphor-conceptual-art/</guid>
      <description>Non-linguistic artworks such as painting, installation, sculpture, etc., often use metaphor to somehow convey their meaning, and their cognitive and artistic effects. Consider Banksy’s small mural in Essex, consisting of five pigeons holding up signs reading ‘go back to Africa’, ‘migrants not welcome’, and ‘keep off our worms’ towards a colourful swallow. The work has been interpreted as a satirical metaphor, potently mocking the rise of anti-immigration sentiment in Britain today (Sinclair &amp;amp; Pringle, 2017: 32) (while the piece does use words, the metaphor itself isn’t linguistic).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Borders of Perception</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/borders-of-perception/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/borders-of-perception/</guid>
      <description>What can we perceive, in a metaphysical sense of the question – what legitimately is a target of a perceptual state? For a long while, in philosophy this venerable debate has concerned the issue of what the objects of perception are, sensory objects as they have been recently labeled (Nanay 2013). Yet there is no agreement at all among philosophers on which are such objects – for some intuitionists, even abstract objects can be perceived, while for some others, the so-called indirect realists, the only objects that are properly perceived are sense-data, mind-dependent entities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aesthetics of action, arts of action</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/aesthetics-of-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/aesthetics-of-action/</guid>
      <description>High art culture has tended to focus on the arts of objects and largely ignored the arts of action. These are the arts designed to call forth activity from their audience, for the sake of that audience’s appreciation of their own activity. I mean things like: rock climbing, games, improvised communal dance, and social food rituals. These arts are either marginalized by high art culture, or they are awkwardly squeezed to fit into the paradigm of the object arts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Beautiful Summer (Online)</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/summer2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/summer2020/</guid>
      <description>From June to August 2020, the Aesthetic Perception and Cognition project at Uppsala University will organise a series of online discussion seminars on central topics in philosophical aesthetics.
For these seminars, we have invited a group of wonderful people to contribute short essays, which will set a starting point for reflection and friendly debate. We&amp;rsquo;re thrilled to present our full schedule below.
The plan is simple. We will meet on Zoom weekly, from mid-June until early August.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading group Aesthetic Practices</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/reading-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/reading-group/</guid>
      <description>People’s engagement with art is highly conventionalised and habitual. Within specific cultures and time periods we can look for aesthetic practices in order to understand better the expectations people have of art, and the values they associate with it. We can take such practices to codify dominant assumptions about what art is and about how we ought to treat it. In particular, a careful analysis of aesthetic practice can help us answer the question: What are the assumptions about the role of perception and cognition in our engagement with art that underpin the way people in fact engage with art?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mary Mothersill</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/quote/mothersill/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 12:18:46 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/quote/mothersill/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robert Bridges</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/quote/bridges/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 12:18:46 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/quote/bridges/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Cornerstone of Philosophical Aesthetics?</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/a-cornerstone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/a-cornerstone/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The cornerstone of philosophical aesthetics, conceived as an area of philosophy primarily concerned with aesthetic and artistic experience, has long been its connection with perception. Ever since the formal inception of the discipline in the mid-eighteenth century, aesthetics (from the Greek aesthesis) has taken that which pertains to the senses, or sense perception, as its subject-matter (Baumgarten 1750; Kant 1790). More particularly, the study of aesthetics has typically concerned itself with the perceptual experience of aesthetic value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bibliography</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/teaching/bibliography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 12:20:58 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/teaching/bibliography/</guid>
      <description>Our investigation is firmly lodged between several on-going international debates and draws on the work produced in those contexts. Here you can find a list of key references.
References Audi, R. 2013. Moral Perception. Princeton, NJ: Princeton University Press.
Baumgarten, A. 1970. Aesthetica. Hildesheim &amp;amp; New York: Georg Olms. First published 1750.
Beardsley, M. C. 1981. Aesthetics, Problems in the Philosophy of Criticism. London: Hackett.
Bergqvist, A. &amp;amp; Cowan, R. 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aesthetics, Character, and Conduct</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/reading-group-spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/reading-group-spring/</guid>
      <description>Standardly we think of aesthetic value as something attached to things we can see, hear, or taste. But what about the value realised in good character, or in an apt moral outlook? Can such values ever be aesthetic? Can aesthetic judgment be relevant for the proper assessment of human character and conduct? We will discuss these and more specific questions in light of two historical authors: Hume and Schiller.
Meeting time: Tuesday 12:30-14:00 (fortnightly)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
