<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research &amp; Ideas on Aesthetic Perception &amp; Cognition</title>
    <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research &amp; Ideas on Aesthetic Perception &amp; Cognition</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 15:45:06 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Borders of Perception</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/borders-of-perception/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/borders-of-perception/</guid>
      <description>What can we perceive, in a metaphysical sense of the question – what legitimately is a target of a perceptual state? For a long while, in philosophy this venerable debate has concerned the issue of what the objects of perception are, sensory objects as they have been recently labeled (Nanay 2013). Yet there is no agreement at all among philosophers on which are such objects – for some intuitionists, even abstract objects can be perceived, while for some others, the so-called indirect realists, the only objects that are properly perceived are sense-data, mind-dependent entities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aesthetics of action, arts of action</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/aesthetics-of-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/aesthetics-of-action/</guid>
      <description>High art culture has tended to focus on the arts of objects and largely ignored the arts of action. These are the arts designed to call forth activity from their audience, for the sake of that audience’s appreciation of their own activity. I mean things like: rock climbing, games, improvised communal dance, and social food rituals. These arts are either marginalized by high art culture, or they are awkwardly squeezed to fit into the paradigm of the object arts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Cornerstone of Philosophical Aesthetics?</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/a-cornerstone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/ideas/a-cornerstone/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The cornerstone of philosophical aesthetics, conceived as an area of philosophy primarily concerned with aesthetic and artistic experience, has long been its connection with perception. Ever since the formal inception of the discipline in the mid-eighteenth century, aesthetics (from the Greek aesthesis) has taken that which pertains to the senses, or sense perception, as its subject-matter (Baumgarten 1750; Kant 1790). More particularly, the study of aesthetics has typically concerned itself with the perceptual experience of aesthetic value.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>