<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on Aesthetic Perception &amp; Cognition</title>
    <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on Aesthetic Perception &amp; Cognition</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2019 15:53:27 +0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop Aesthetic Practices</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/workshop2021jan/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/workshop2021jan/</guid>
      <description>The Aesthetics Perception and Cognition Project organises a one-day, online workshop, which will take place on the 12th of January 2020. The theme of the workshop is Aesthetic Practices. For more information about the workshop, and about how to participate via Zoom, please get in touch with maarten.steenhagen@filosofi.uu.se
Workshop: Aesthetic Practices, 12 January 2021 Schedule : Welcome: 10:00-10:15
 Session A: 10:15-11:15  Jon Robson &amp;lsquo;Over-Appreciating Appreciation&amp;rsquo; (Co-author Rebecca Wallbank) Response: Nick Wiltsher   Virtual coffee break: 11:15-11:30</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Aesthetic Life</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/reading-group-autumn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/reading-group-autumn/</guid>
      <description>Think of the aesthetic value realised in good character, in good urban planning, in one’s personal style, of the ugliness of consumerism, etc. What is the place of such values in our lives? And what is the place of those values in a theory of aesthetic experience or judgment?
Discussing the place of aesthetic value in our lives, broadly construed, is likely to help us to be more critical of the idea that aesthetic experience is at root sensory or perceptual, considering life is about so much more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Beautiful Summer (Online)</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/summer2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/summer2020/</guid>
      <description>From June to August 2020, the Aesthetic Perception and Cognition project at Uppsala University will organise a series of online discussion seminars on central topics in philosophical aesthetics.
For these seminars, we have invited a group of wonderful people to contribute short essays, which will set a starting point for reflection and friendly debate. We&#39;re thrilled to present our full schedule below.
The plan is simple. We will meet on Zoom weekly, from mid-June until early August.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading group Aesthetic Practices</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/reading-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/reading-group/</guid>
      <description>People’s engagement with art is highly conventionalised and habitual. Within specific cultures and time periods we can look for aesthetic practices in order to understand better the expectations people have of art, and the values they associate with it. We can take such practices to codify dominant assumptions about what art is and about how we ought to treat it. In particular, a careful analysis of aesthetic practice can help us answer the question: What are the assumptions about the role of perception and cognition in our engagement with art that underpin the way people in fact engage with art?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aesthetics, Character, and Conduct</title>
      <link>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/reading-group-spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aestheticperceptioncognition.se/events/reading-group-spring/</guid>
      <description>Standardly we think of aesthetic value as something attached to things we can see, hear, or taste. But what about the value realised in good character, or in an apt moral outlook? Can such values ever be aesthetic? Can aesthetic judgment be relevant for the proper assessment of human character and conduct? We will discuss these and more specific questions in light of two historical authors: Hume and Schiller.
 Meeting time: Tuesday 12:30-14:00 (fortnightly)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>